Monika Novackova

School of Global Studies, University of Sussex ADDRESS: Personal websites LinkedIn

Falmer, Brighton

BN1 901, United Kingdom

0774 180 4494 PHONE:

monika.novac@gmail.com EMAIL:

CITIZIENSHIP: Czech Republic, European Union. Indefinite Leave to Remain in the UK granted

Data scientist, climate economist and recent PhD graduate is searching for an experience as data analyst in private sector. Demonstrable skills in advanced statistical analysis and econometric modelling using Python, R, STATA and Excel. Experienced in communicating concepts to co-workers from various backgrounds.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Current since 2017

Data analyst in Sustainability, UNIVERSITY OF SUSSEX, Brighton Application of statistical and machine learning models to analyse effects of droughts on food security in Kenya using R and Python Supervisors: Prof. Martin Todd, Dr. Pedram Rowhani

Collected data in a systematic and safe way. Analysed complex data and presented emerging conclusions and concepts. Developed statistical and econometric models using R and Excel. Meeting regular deadlines. Interacting with colleagues from diverse professional backgrounds to successfully work towards common goals.

2015-2016

Teaching at THE UNIVERSITY OF SUSSEX, Brighton

Climate Change Economics and Statistical Analysis in STATA

Communicated complex ideas effectively to a range of audiences. Sensitive to the needs of others.

2012-2013

Data scientist at Centrum Wiskunde & Informatica (CWI), Amsterdam Statistical analysis and forecasting using R and SQL

Experience in quantitative analysis. Ability to present and organise large amounts of information in a clear manner. Negotiating skills.

2011

Data analyst at PILSNER URQUELL, A.S., Prague Market analysis at the large beer manufacturer

Succeeded in a highly competitive application procedure. Using analytic and statistical skills accompanied with economic background for better description of beer market dynamics. Improved beer demand models. Presentation of concepts to the company's executive management.

EDUCATION

2014-2018

Ph.D. in Economics, University of Sussex, UK

Thesis: "Effects of Sea Level Rise in the United States and climate change perception in the United Kingdom" | Full version

- Managing of complex datasets in a range of different formats
- Analysis of both macro data and survey data
- Application of advanced statistical and econometric methods
- Regression models including instrumental variables and Heckman correction
- The Multisplit lasso and other machine learning methods

Advisors: Prof. Richard Tol, Dr. Alexander Moradi

EDUCATION

2013-2014 Ing. in Econometrics and Operations Research

Faculty of informatics and statistics, **University of Economics in Prague** Thesis: "Application of Time Series Analysis in Predictive Modelling

Advisor: Prof. Roman HUSEK

2011-2013 MSc in Econometrics and Operations Research

Vrije University in Amsterdam

Thesis: "Forecasting of Daily Number of Calls for Firefighters Advisors: Prof. Siem Jan Koopman, Prof. Michael Massmann

2007-2010 Bc. in QUANTITATIVE METHODS IN ECONOMICS, University of Economics in Prague

COMPUTER SKILLS

Advanced Knowledge: Python, R, Excel including contingency tables, statistical analysis

simulations and optimization using the Solver Add-In, LATEX

Intermediate Knowledge: SQL, Git, Web-design (HTML, CSS, JavaScript): Level 1 course run

by Code First: Girls completed in Autumn 2018 (Certificate.pdf)

Basic Knowledge: STATA, ArcGIS, Mathematical Programming (Lingo, Mpl)

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: Fluent, PhD completed in English, TOEFL score 101 in 2014

CZECH: Native language

GERMAN: Basic

OTHER ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Publication with R. Tol: "Effects of sea level rise on economy of the United States", Journal of Environmental Economics and Policy. DOI:10.1080/21606544.2017.1363667

2017 Presenting at the International Conference of Economics and Development (ICED)
Colombo, Sri Lanka, paper Effects of Sea level rise on land values in the United States

2013 Participation in the Econometric Game 2013 organized by the University of Amsterdam

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Learning and improving programming skills beyond statistical programming. At the moment, my main interest is getting experienced in App development skills in Python. I have completed a Web-development course run by *Code First: Girls* in Autumn 2018.

Sports: Running, Cycling, Snowboarding

References available on request